William G. Brooks Papers MS092
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
William G. Brooks Papers
1890 -- 1995
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Brooks, William Gooch
MS092
5.1 Linear Feet 7 boxes, 1 oversize folder
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series: Photographs and Memorabilia, 1911-1915; Delta Upsilon Materials.
Custodial History
UA217 was moved to MS092 and a second series was created.
Accession 2011.076 Delta Upsilon materials: Brooks' son (also William, class of 1952) passed materials along to John Baronian, and following Baronian's death, they came into the possession of Paul Gillespie. Gillespie passed them on to Rocco (Rocky) Carzo who gave them to the Digital Collections and Archives.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of W. G. Brooks' photographs and memorabilia from his time at Tufts College between 1911 and 1915. Photograph albums include tours of the Mandolin and Glee Clubs to New Hampshire, Maine, Connecticut, Michigan, and New York (including photographs of Niagara Falls and the "New Grand Central Station New York City"). Also included are photographs of the Class of 1915, of sports teams and individual photographs of athletes of 1915, and of Tufts honorary and social organizations. The collection also contains photographs of the Delta Upsilon fraternity house, of Junior Week 1914 (with the parade of the Horribles), and of Class Day 1914 (with speakers and the bombardment); photographs of East Hall interior and exterior; group shots of banquets, Delta Upsilon members, and Glee and Mandolin Clubs, individual portraits of the Class of 1915 and Delta Upsilon. Memorabilia includes posters, a scrapbook, music and lyrics for "Parent of Light," the 1915 class song by Brooks, other Tufts related items, and newspaper clippings. Also included in the collection are an Atwater Kent Radio Instruction Book from 1926, a company and product history booklet, and a Radio Log.
Biographical / Historical
William Gooch Brooks (1894-1985) graduated from Tufts College in 1915 with a B.S. in Chemistry. While at Tufts, he was a member of Delta Upsilon fraternity, the Glee and Mandolin Clubs, and the Evening Party Association. Brooks also co-wrote the class song of 1915, "The Parent of Light." After graduation, Brooks managed the Armstrong Cork Co. plant in South Braintree and served on the Braintree Industrial and Business Development Commission. Known as "Mr. Braintree" in business and real estate circles, he was also active in many charitable and civic organizations. A building, street, and baseball field in Braintree were named in his honor. Brooks married Dorothy Foster at Goddard Chapel on June 1, 1917. [A letter to the editor of the Tufts Criterion states that he is married to Helen Hare Brooks.] He had four sons, including William H. Brooks, who graduated from Tufts College in 1954. He died in 1985 at the age of 91.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Brooks, W. G.; Delta Upsilon; Glee Club; Mandolin Club; Atwater Kent Radio Company; Parent of Light; Alumni collections; Student life
- Photographs and Memorabilia, 1905 -- 1995; 1915; MS092.001; 4.6 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs and memorabilia relating to Tufts College and gathered by William Gooch Brooks. This includes photographs of Delta Upsilon, the Glee and Mandolin Clubs, class photographs and posters, music and lyrics for "Parent of Light" a Tufts song by Brooks, interior and exterior photographs of East Hall, a scrapbook, and student portraits and group shots. It also contains Atwater Kent Radio instructions, a history of the Atwater Kent company and its products as well as a radio log from 1926. The series also contains documents and a photo album from the Delta Upsilon fraternity that originally belonged to Brooks. These have been moved from UA217.
  Arrangement
  This series was arranged by subject matter and format. Original order of photo albums was maintained when possible.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Athletics, Student Organizations, Delta Upsilon House, Junior Week, Class Day, 1913 -- 1914; MS092.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Glee and Mandolin Club Trips, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Glee and Mandolin Club Members and Trips, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, Tufts, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.003.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 3)
    Brooks, W. G.; Tufts College
  - Class of 1915 - Portraits 1 of 2, MS092.001.004.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Class of 1915 - Portaits 2 of 2, MS092.001.004.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Class of 1915/Military Portraits, MS092.001.004.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Tufts People and Buildings - Loose pages from Album, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Tufts Student Groups and Activities, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00005; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Photographs of East Hall, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00006; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - Misc. Group Shots, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00007; Brooks, W. G. (Box Shared 132)
    Ivy Society - Junior Honor Society photo has label in front identifying group.
  - Banquet photographs, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00008; Brooks, W. G. (Box Shared 132)
  - Class photographs, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00009; Brooks, W. G. (Box Shared 132)
  - Tufts Memorabilia, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00010; Brooks, W. G. (Box Shared 132)
    Memorabilia includes student-made posters regarding in-coming Freshman, and a Tufts College poster from 1911
  - Glee and Mandolin Club photographs, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00011; Brooks, W. G. (Box Shared 132)
  - Delta Upsilon Bulletins, 1913 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00012; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    1913 and 1915 - excludes 1914.
    Brooks, W. G.; Tufts College; Delta Upsilon
  - Music, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.001.004.00013; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    Parent of Light; Brooks, W. G.; Tufts College
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1978 -- 1995; MS092.001.004.00014; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    Brooks, W. G.
  - Atwater Kent Radio Instructions, 1926; MS092.001.004.00015; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    Atwater Kent Radio Instruction Book from 1926, a company and product history booklet, and a Radio Log.
    Atwater Kent Radio Company; Brooks, W. G.
  - Official Football Score Cards - Bowdoin v. Tufts, 1905; MS092.001.004.00016; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    Bowdoin v. Tufts October 23, 1905 and schedule of games
    Football; Brooks, W. G.
  - Class Day Music, 1905; MS092.001.004.00017; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
    Class Day; Brooks, W. G.
  - Delta Upsilon Envelope, 1905; MS092.001.004.00018; Brooks, W. G. (Box 4)
  - 3Ps, Jackson College, Unidentified, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    The sub-items for this record are individual photographs from a scrapbook page.
    - Pen, Paint and Pretzels, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00001.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 1, Photo 1
    - Jackson College, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00001.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 1, Photo 2
    - Unidentified Male Students, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00001.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 1, Photo 1
    - Unidentified Male Students, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00001.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 1, Photo 2
  - Group Trips, Football Squad, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut Mid-Year Glee Club Trip, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 1
    - Christmas Trip, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 2
    - Christmas Trip, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 3
    - Mid-Year Glee and Mandolin Club Trip, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 4
    - Christmas Trip, 1911-12 Franklin, N.H., 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00005; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 5
    - Group Trip - unidentified, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00006; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 2, Photo 6
    - Football Squad, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00002.00007; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 2, Photo 1
  - Unidentified Play Cast, Football Players, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Unidentified Play Cast, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00003.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 3, Photo 1
    - Mitchell, Angell, Merrill, Field [Football Players], 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00003.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 3, Photo 1
  - Coach Tobin, Captain Merrill - Football, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Coach Tobin, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00004.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 4, Photo 1
    - Capt. Merrill, 1911 -- 1912; MS092.001.005.00004.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 4, Photo 2
  - Honor Societies, Sports Team Captains, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00005; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Tower Cross, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00005.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 5, Photo 1
    - Ivy Society, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00005.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 5, Photo 2
    - Sword and Shield, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00005.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 5, Photo 3
    - Capt. Adams, Football, 1912; MS092.001.005.00005.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 5, Photo 1
    - Capt. Bennett, Baseball, 1913; MS092.001.005.00005.00005; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 5, Photo 2
    - Capt. Atwater, Track, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00005.00006; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 5, Photo 3
  - Track Squad, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00006; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Track Squad, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00006.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 6, Photo 1
  - Sports Team Managers, Football Squad, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00007; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
    - Mgr. Atwater, Baseball, 1913; MS092.001.005.00007.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 7, Photo 1
    - Mgr. Sterling, Track, 1912 -- 1913; MS092.001.005.00007.00002; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 7, Photo 2
    - Mgr. Bush, Football, 1912; MS092.001.005.00007.00003; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Recto 7, Photo 3
    - Football Squad, 1912; MS092.001.005.00007.00004; Brooks, W. G. (Box 5)
      Verso 7, Photo 1
- Delta Upsilon Materials, 1890 -- 1920; 1915; MS092.002; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series was moved from UA217 and contain documents and a photo album from the Delta Upsilon fraternity that also originally belonged to W. G. Brooks.
  - Delta Upsilon Photographs, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.002.001.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 1)
  - Delta Upsilon Founding Documents, 1890 -- 1920; MS092.002.001.00002 (Box 1)
    This folder consists of documents pertaining to the founding of the Delta Upsilon fraternity at Tufts College in 1894 as well as miscellaneous documents from the fraternity's early years at Tufts.
    Tufts College; Delta Upsilon
  - Delta Upsilon Treasurer's Documents, 1890 -- 1920; MS092.002.001.00003 (Box 1)
    This folder consists of treasurer's documents pertaining to the early years of the Delta Upsilon fraternity at Tufts College.
    Delta Upsilon; Brooks, W. G.; Tufts College; Delta Upsilon
  - Delta Upsilon - Correspondence, 1890 -- 1920; MS092.002.001.00004 (Box 1)
    This folder consists of correspondence between fraternity brothers and members of Tufts College.
    Delta Upsilon; Tufts College; Delta Upsilon
  - [No. 10 Dean Hall - Interior Photographs], 1911 -- 1915; MS092.002.001.00005 (Box 1)
    Buildings
  - Eightieth Annual Convention Delta Upsilon, Cleveland, 1914-10; MS092.002.001.00006 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 5)
    photographic print
  - Delta Upsilon Photo Album, 1911 -- 1915; MS092.002.002.00001; Brooks, W. G. (Box 2)
    Delta Upsilon; Brooks, W. G.; Tufts College